For many of us, there’s nothing better than burying our head in a good book.
对我们很多人来说，没有什么比埋头读一本好书更惬意的事了。
Whether it’s a gripping crime story or a biography of someone’s amazing life, it’s good to read a book to switch off from the distractions of everyday life and help us relax.
不管是扣人心弦的犯罪小说，还是记录某人传奇一生的传记，捧起一本书，暂时抛开日常生活的纷扰，让我们放松身心。
Maybe that’s why some of them are actually being prescribed as a remedy to sickness.
或许正因如此，有些书甚至被当作治疗疾病的药方。
It may seem obvious that reading is good for us.
阅读对我们有益，这似乎是显而易见的事实。
It can be educational, and, as some say, it can ‘broaden the mind’.
阅读有教育意义，而且正如有些人所说，它还能“开阔眼界”。
A good novel can make us happy or sad, or make us cry as we empathise with characters.
一本好小说能让我们或喜或悲，能让我们因共情书中人物而潸然泪下。
The power of books was recognised a few years ago by the British charity Reading Agency, who published a list of books that doctors could offer to patients, tackling topics from depression to dementia to chronic pain.
几年前，英国慈善机构“阅读社”就意识到了书籍的力量，该机构发布了一份书单，医生可以将这些书推荐给患者，内容涵盖抑郁症、痴呆症、慢性疼痛等多个主题。
It called this ‘bibliotherapy’ and it’s become so successful that it's about to be extended to children as well.
这种疗法被称为“阅读疗法”，如今它大获成功，即将推广到儿童群体中。
Professor Philip Davis studies the effects of literature at Liverpool University and is author of a book called Reading for Life.
菲利普·戴维斯教授在利物浦大学研究文学的影响，他还是《终身阅读》一书的作者。
He studies people in reading groups and found that it’s reading literature – written work thought to have artistic merit, that has the best effect.
他对读书小组的成员进行研究后发现，阅读文学作品——那些被认为具有艺术价值的书面作品，能带来最佳效果。
He told the BBC that when reading something for pleasure, “…the brain begins to work from different parts, from a different hemisphere and it gets excited, it gets pre-emotional – and you can see the brain coming to life.”
他在接受BBC采访时表示，当人们为了消遣而阅读时，“大脑的不同区域、不同半球都会开始运作，大脑会变得兴奋，产生前置情绪反应——你能看到大脑焕发出活力。”
Of course, it’s easy in our smartphone generation to ditch a good book and fiddle with our phones instead.
当然，在这个智能手机时代，人们很容易丢下好书，转而摆弄手机。
But opening up a paperback could be a simple way to help boost or maintain our mental health.
但翻开一本平装书，或许是提升或维持心理健康的一个简单方法。
It's thought they can help you set targets and find focus. And they may allow you to see that awkward situation you've been anxious about for weeks from someone else's perspective.
据说读书能帮助人们设定目标、找到专注力，还能让你从别人的视角，看待那件困扰了你好几周的尴尬事。
If you’re not an avid reader it can be hard to know where to begin.
如果你不是一名热衷阅读的人，可能会不知道从何入手。
If the Reading Agency book list doesn’t appeal, you could to read book reviews, visit a library or bookshop or ask a friend.
要是“阅读社”的书单不合你意，你可以读读书评、逛逛图书馆或书店，或是问问朋友的建议。
Once you’ve found the right text, you’ll be hooked!
一旦找到适合自己的书，你就会爱不释手！
And if you still love your technology, you could always use an e-reader.
而如果你依旧钟情于电子产品，也完全可以用电子阅读器来阅读。